<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Yellow Dusk</title>
    <link>https://yellowdus.cc/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Yellow Dusk</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 08:57:08 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://yellowdus.cc/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Reliance</title>
      <link>https://yellowdus.cc/blog/self-reliance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 08:57:08 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yellowdus.cc/blog/self-reliance/</guid>
      <description>Emerson writes, in &amp;ldquo;Self-Reliance&amp;rdquo;—an essay that thrills me and stings me today just the same as it did when I first encountered it, nearly a decade ago—of the ultimate justification of self-reliance:
 This is the ultimate fact which we so quickly reach on this, as on every topic, the resolution of all into the ever-blessed ONE. Self-existence is the attribute of the Supreme Cause, and it constitutes the measure of good by the degree in which it enters into all lower forms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dialogue</title>
      <link>https://yellowdus.cc/blog/dialogue/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 07:59:33 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yellowdus.cc/blog/dialogue/</guid>
      <description>A: Enough. I will have done with improving myself: with guilt, with shame, with this perpetual sense of insufficiency. It wastes me. Enough.
B: So you are happy with who you are?
A: Happy? I am who I am, that sufficies. What need do I have for happiness atop the fact?
B: But surely you are better now than you once were. [B draws A&amp;rsquo;s mind to recollection of his awkward and intolerable younger self.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Other Minds (Ashbery)</title>
      <link>https://yellowdus.cc/blog/otherminds/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2020 20:14:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yellowdus.cc/blog/otherminds/</guid>
      <description>Take this poem by John Ashbery, published in his 1995 collection, Can You Hear, Bird?:
 A Poem of Unrest
Men duly understand the river of life,
misconstruing it, as it widens and its cities grow
dark and denser, always farther away.
And of course that remote denseness suits
us, as lambs and clover might have
if things had been built to order differently.
But since I don&amp;rsquo;t understand myself, only segments</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Much-prompted mares</title>
      <link>https://yellowdus.cc/blog/much-prompted_mares/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2020 09:02:39 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yellowdus.cc/blog/much-prompted_mares/</guid>
      <description>It is puzzling why Parmenides, staid prophet of the inalterable One, should open his great poem with the depiction of a journey, of much-prompted mares that carry him to the limits of his heart&amp;rsquo;s desire, straining at the carriage, guided by a coterie of maidens. Yet how else except by such an image was he to capture the delirious freedom of the fetters in which Justice has bound the Whole? How other than through the &amp;ldquo;stationary movement&amp;rdquo; (Valery) of metaphor was he to give voice to his unshaken ecstasy?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chaos and Oblivion</title>
      <link>https://yellowdus.cc/blog/chaos_and_oblivion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 07:43:54 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yellowdus.cc/blog/chaos_and_oblivion/</guid>
      <description>It is firmly established that the stories of the Zhuangzi accreted over an extended period and are not the work of a single hand. Even the traditional view that Zhuang Zhou himself wrote only the inner chapters (1-7) is suspect. Hell, not even the mere historical existence of Master Zhuang is above doubt. Nevertheless.
Nevertheless, there is a thematic unity to the inner chapters that dissipates (but does not vanish) in the outer and miscellaneous chapters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Thought Regarding Koans</title>
      <link>https://yellowdus.cc/blog/a_thought_regarding_koans/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 10:34:09 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yellowdus.cc/blog/a_thought_regarding_koans/</guid>
      <description>Over the past two years, I have been slowly and haphazardly developing a meditation practice, predominantly in the Zen tradition. The details of what I do have changed over time; currently I am working on a form of koan training. Rough details are:
 I use the bamboo method of breathing, where each exhalation is broken up by brief pauses (rather than releasing my breath continuously) I breathe in a cycle of one long exhalation (seven bamboo segments) followed by four short exhalations (two bamboo segments) With each bamboo segment, I focus on one syllable of the koan  The koan I am using, adapted from a translation by Katuski Sekida, records a conversation between the monk Seizei and the Zen master Sōzan:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Idealism and Poetry</title>
      <link>https://yellowdus.cc/blog/emerson_nature_1837/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 20:17:49 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yellowdus.cc/blog/emerson_nature_1837/</guid>
      <description>1. Insignificance Near the start of Nature, Ralph Waldo Emerson distinguishes two senses of his key term: nature as all that is not myself (including my body), and nature as all that is not artifice. But, he says, no confusion will arise from this, for all the effects of human artifice&amp;hellip;
 &amp;hellip;taken together are so insignificant, a little chipping, baking, patching, and washing, that in an impression so grand as that of the world on the human mind, they do not vary the result.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debths (Susan Howe)</title>
      <link>https://yellowdus.cc/blog/debths/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 15:29:11 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yellowdus.cc/blog/debths/</guid>
      <description>[1] &amp;ldquo;THE NAME AND THE SOUL&amp;rdquo;
“The soul,” Susan Howe tells us, “appears or occurs as something we feel compelled to live into or move toward as if it were there floating a little apart and at an angle or” (20). The ending of that quote is no error: the other possibilities go unsaid. The soul, on this model, is not a possession. Ever out of reach, it draws us onward.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>